Hey English learners, welcome to this A1
English listening practice video. I hope
you're doing well and that you're ready
to practice your listening
comprehension.
Today I want to talk about camping. Why?
Well, I like camping and recently I went
camping twice with my family. So, I want
to talk about this and tell you why I
like it and uh how to camp. So, I hope
you enjoy this video and I know it will
be good practice for your listening. And
before we start, I want to mention that
if you want to support me and my content
and help me continue to make content for
English learners like this video, please
sign up to support me through my
membership and you'll get extra content
and training and it really helps me. So,
if you want to help me and receive my
training, then click on the link below
to sign up. Okay, let's talk about
camping. Uh, recently I went camping
with my family. Uh, we went camping um
very close to my house. So, these were
short camping trips, just one night
each, but they were fun, and we really
enjoyed them. Where do we go camping?
Uh, in the US, when people want to go
camping,
where do they go? We usually go to
specific
parks. Um, usually government parks like
uh a state park, a regional park or
whatever. We go to government parks and
it's in nature but it's more controlled.
So, it's safe. Uh, you have to pay to uh
go inside the park. You have to pay to
camp there. So, it's very controlled and
safe, but it's still nature. But uh
normally people don't just go into the
forest and camp.
People might do that, but I think it's
more common to go to these uh parks
where they have uh campgrounds as we
call them. So, there are different
sites, different places in the
campground where people can camp. Um, so
normally you're next to other people.
you're close to other campers.
And uh at these campgrounds
uh they provide
everything you need um for uh like water
uh bathrooms.
Um
fire pits like where you make a fire. Uh
tables
so you can sit and eat. uh a parking
space for your car. Um there are trees
usually. Uh so um they provide a lot of
stuff, but of course uh you need to
bring your own tent or maybe uh you can
camp in an RV as we call it. Uh these
are these big vehicles uh where you can
sleep in them and there's a bathroom and
a kitchen. Maybe many people in the US
uh like to camp in an RV. Uh I prefer
tent camping. When I go camping, I sleep
in a tent. Uh these are different types
of experiences.
Tent camping and RV camping are very
different, but they're both fun.
And sleeping in a tent is not very
comfortable, but it's an interesting
experience. Uh, I think that part of the
fun of camping is being a little
uncomfortable. Uh, because it's part of
the experience to be in nature,
uh, to not have the same comfortable
things that you have at home. It's part
of the fun. So, uh, the tent that we use
is called an instant tent. So, this
means that you can set it up. You can uh
put it together uh very quickly, like in
an instant. Um because there are other
tense that are much harder to set up. Uh
and it can take a long time to set those
tense up. I've seen uh people struggle
for a long time to set up those types of
tents. But the instant tent that we have
is very easy to set up and you can do it
very quickly. So, uh, we set up the tent
when we arrive at the campsite because
you don't want to wait until nighttime
to set up the tent. Uh you want the
light
and uh this tent has doors and windows
and you can leave the roof uncovered so
that you can see the sky. Uh it's really
cool. And of course we have sleeping
bags.
uh these things where we uh can sleep
in. And uh sometimes people use air
mattresses where they inflate and it's
like a bed. Um and uh there are other
types of uh beds to sleep on in tents.
And um in some areas where people camp,
there are uh animals
and you can hear them at night when
you're in your tent. Um when we camped,
we heard coyotes at night. Uh but this
is okay. It's not uh scary or anything.
It's part of the fun. Of course, if you
camp in the mountains and you hear a
bear,
that's a little scary. But, um, for us,
we like to be in nature around animals.
It's fun. And normally when you sleep in
a tent, you wake up early because the uh
sun comes up and everything becomes
light. So it's uh hard to sleep more
when everything is light around you. Um,
how about cooking? Uh, I love cooking
when camping because uh we cook over the
fire. So, we use the fire that we make.
I start the fire and we cook over the
fire. We use skewers. These long sticks.
We use skewers and we put the food on
the skewer and put it over the fire to
cook. Uh, we cooked hot dogs. So, we
cooked hot dogs. We put the hot dog on
the skewer and put it over the fire and
it cooks. And we also cooked meatballs.
Uh, we put them on the skewers as well
and cooked them over the fire. And we
cooked marshmallows. We roasted
marshmallows, as we say. Uh, this is one
of the funnest parts of camping,
roasting marshmallows. They're delicious
and you can use them to make s'mores. Uh
s'mores are these sandwiches with graham
crackers, these sweet crackers, and a
roasted marshmallow and chocolate. If
you combine these uh into a sandwich,
this is called a s'more. So, uh I love
making uh s'mores and roasting
marshmallows.
Uh some people prefer to bring pans and
pots and cook over the fire on a pan. We
don't do this. We just use skewers,
these sticks. Uh I love this part of
camping. It's really fun to make your
food over the fire and it's fun to sit
around the fire. So, why do people go
camping? Uh, it's a lot of fun. You can
spend time in nature.
You can change your routine a little
bit.
uh you uh do something
different when you camp, you sleep
somewhere different, you cook
differently.
Uh it's a different experience and it is
interesting to change your routine and
it's even fun to set up the camp. Uh,
it's fun to feel like you are surviving
in nature. Even if it's not
in a forest or in the mountains, even in
a park, it's still fun. It feels good to
set up the tent and build the fire and
cook and all of that. And it's fun to
sit around the campfire
and spend time with your family or your
friends and talk and tell stories
and make memories.
Some of my greatest memories from my
childhood
are my memories of camping. I had so
much fun camping as a kid and I hope
that my children also make memories uh
while camping and I hope that when they
are adults uh they can remember these
experiences
of camping with their family. So, there
are many reasons why people like
camping. Uh, and I recommend that you
try it if you're able to, if you can.
So, hopefully this video was interesting
and hopefully you were able to
understand. Well, if my content is
helpful for you, please consider
supporting me by becoming a member. Uh
the link is down below. And when you
sign up, you'll also get training and
extra content. So, uh please consider
doing that. Thank you all for watching
this video and I'll talk to you in the
next